Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太と
ひびと
栄光の日 生まれの弟･日々人＞
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
＜日本人初の
ﾑｰﾝｳｫｰｶｰとなった日々人は➡
月面での事故の影響による
パニック障害で前線から外され➡
However, a lunar accident has left him struggling on the sidelines, suffering from panic disorder.
もがき苦しんでいる｡
復帰をかけた試験は目前だ＞
But he's about to take a test to return to active duty.
＜一方 日々人のはるか後ろから
月を目指し始めた六太は➡
Meanwhile, older brother Mutta continues his long quest.
ケンジや新田とともに
バトラー室長に呼び出され➡
Chief Butler has summoned Mutta, Kenji, and Nitta to discuss their future missions.
今後の任務について告げられる｡
果たして その結果は!?＞
What will their fate be?
I can't get lost in what I'm doing, nothing works out
I don't want these endlessly dull days
I hope I can move on
before the call of freedom drags me away
What's your wish?
I just want some real courage
We all stare doubt in the face, every one of us
Isn't the unpredictability of life the fun of it?
Devote your life to that dream you can't express
Let's go, advance against the wind, our road is long
Embrace the pain of it too
Take a big breath now, and yell
Big Bang! Chase it without fear!
I want to dream so badly it amazes me
There's cowardice in the way of your true wish
Rip that hot veil aside
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]♬～
#89 Last Words
Morning Radio is here to kick off your day!
[ﾗｼﾞｵ](ＤＪ)聞くと元気になる
モーニングレディオ！
Time for the Q&A corner. Yeah!
キューアンドエー
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]Ｑ＆Ａのコーナー イエーッ！
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]ロスにお住まいのカール君
８才からの質問！
We have a question from eight-year-old Carl, out in LA.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]人が何人か乗っている
エレベーターの中でオナラを➡
"If you fart in a crowded elevator, what should you do?"
してしまいました｡ああいう時
どうすればいいですか？
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]なるほどぉ あるよね～｡
わかるよ カール君｡
Ah, we've all been through that.
I get your drift, Carl.
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]よし 教えてあげよう！
そんな時はね➡
Okay, here's the answer...
When that happens,
｢あれ？なんか臭くない？｣
って言えばいいよ！
to shift the blame, you say, "Huh? Does something smell?"
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]♬～
なんば
(南波六太)まったく…朝から
低レベルなラジオだぜ｡
Man, this show's a crummy way to start the morning.
今朝はずいぶん
ボ～ッとしてんなぁ ムッちゃん｡
You were pretty out of it this morning, Mu.
昨日の酒が残ってんの？
Still a little hung over?
いや…寝過ぎたせいで
逆に眠いんだよ｡
No, I'm sleepy because I slept too much.
あれ？日々人…｡
Huh? Hibito?
Hmm?
なんか臭くない？
やめてくれっ｡
Does something smell?
Cut it out!
《…と 意地のウソをつらぬいた
自分をほめてあげたい》
I should feel good about myself
for pulling off that lie.
《本当は夕べ
ピーディー
日々人のＰＤが気になり…》
Honestly, last night, I was worried about Hibito's panic disorder.
ムッちゃん
ＰＤってわかる？
Mu,
do you know what "PD" stands for?
ＰＤ？
ああ プリティドッグな｡
"PD"?
Oh.
You mean Pretty Dog. What about it?
それがどうした？
ちげぇよ｡
Not that!
あ あれっ違った？
じゃ じゃあ あれか！
Huh? That's wrong?
Th-Then it must be...
パラジウム 元素記号 ｐｄ｡
Palladium?
The chemical symbol is Pd.
"Panic disorder."
パニックディスオーダー
パニック障害のことだよ｡
It's an anxiety disorder.
ああ なるほど｡そっちか｡
Oh, that's what you meant.
パニック障害？
Panic disorder?
現在
《ネットで詳しく調べたり➡
I was busy researching on the Internet and thinking things over...
あれこれ考えているうちに…》
《朝がきてしまったのだ》
And the next thing I knew, it was morning.
Which means I didn't get any sleep!
《要するに寝不足…》
(せりか)おはようございます！
南波さん！
Good morning, Nanba!
Huh? Hmm?
あっ せりかさん！おはよう！
Serika! Good morning!
今日から新しい訓練ですよね｡
お互い 頑張りましょう！
You're starting a new training program today, right?
Let's do our best.
はっ はい！
そうしましょう！
Y-Yes! Let's do that!
はぁ…あ…｡
あは…フフ…｡
Yeah, she's so cute in the morning!
《いやぁ～ 朝からなんて
カワイイ人だぁ～！➡
That woke me right up!
一瞬 目ぇ覚めたもん》
《プリティドッグ…》
Pretty Dog...
Well, Hibito should be fine.
《まぁ 日々人なら大丈夫だろう》
《調べた感じだと
同じＰＤでも日々人は➡
Based on my reading, Hibito's panic disorder isn't that severe.
まだ発作が起こりくい方だ｡➡
車の運転とか
タクシーに乗ることさえ➡
Some people can't even drive or ride in taxis.
困難な場合も よくあるようだが》
《日々人の場合
その点は大丈夫そうだし…》
But Hibito seems to have no trouble with those.
⦅あっ！⦆
《あいつなら 楽勝で
試験に合格できるはずだ》
He should be able to pass the test easily.
もし俺なら…➡
If I were in your shoes,
多分 逃げそうな気がするけど…
その試験から｡
I'd probably run away from the test.
でも 大雑把なお前は
迷っても結局やるんだろ｡
But while a carefree guy like you may worry, you'll go through with it.
That's how you are.
そういう奴だ｡俺がここで
やめとけっつっても➡
Right now, if I told you to quit, you'd still take the test.
絶対やるんだよ｡
心ん中に
｢絶対｣を持ってる奴だからな｡
Because deep down, you have things within you that are definite.
現在
さてと…ンンッ！
Okay, then...
試験まで あと３日｡
Three days left until the test!
楽しみだ｡
I can't wait.
うう…あ～…｡
You okay, Mutta?
(職員)大丈夫か？ムッタ｡
Oh, Vince.
あっ ビンスさん｡
おはよ…｡
(ビンス)２分遅刻です｡
Good morning—
You're two minutes late.
Oh, sorry.
はっ…あ すみません
フラフラしてたもんで｡
I couldn't walk straight.
ひどい顔ですね｡
寝不足ですか｡
You look terrible. Not enough sleep?
早寝早起きを心がけて下さい｡
お…ハイッ｡
Please try to get to sleep early and to wake early.
Yes, sir.
おお…あ ああ…｡
And so, you three are supposed to run over to the chief's office, one at a time.
というわけだから あんたら
３人とも今すぐ１人ずつ➡
ダッシュで室長室に行きなさい｡
バトラー室長が 呼んでるわ｡
Chief Butler wants to see you.
失礼します！
Excuse me!
現在
ミスター･ナンバ｡➡
Mr. Nanba...
君のプライベートにまで
口出しするつもりは➡
I don't intend to pry into your personal life.
ありませんが これから君は
私と同じマニュアル書を読み…｡
But starting now, we will be reading the same manuals,
(ビンス)同じ船室の空気を吸い
同じシートに座り➡
breathing the same cabin air, sitting in the same seats,
同じ訓練を受けるんです｡
and undergoing the same training.
私のリズムに
ついてこられるようにして下さい｡
You need to be able to follow my rhythm.
はい！
Yes, sir!
それが私のバックアップクルーに
選ばれた者のつとめです｡
That is your job as my backup.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ナンバ･ヒビト➡
Nanba Hibito, Azuma Takio, Murasaki Sansei.
アズマ･タキオ
ムラサキ･サンセイ…｡
The next Japanese astronaut to go the moon...
次に月へ行く日本人は…｡
君だ｡ナンバ･ムッタ｡
will be you, Nanba Mutta.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)その前に一度 控えの
経験を積んでもらう｡
But first, you must build experience on a backup crew.
ビンセント･ボールド飛行士の
バックアップクルｰに任命する｡
You have been assigned as Vincent Bold's backup.
M-Me?
《お 俺が!?》
現在
《俺が 月ミッションに…》
I've been assigned to a lunar mission!
《しかもビンスさんの
バックアップ！》
And I get to be Vince's backup!
(職員)ようこそ オリオンへ｡
Welcome to Orion.
This is it... I finally made it!
《きた！とうとうきた！》
We'll be sitting in the left rear seat, up top.
我々が座るシートは
上段左奥です｡
はい｡
Yes, sir.
い 一瞬だけ
座ってみてもいいですか？
C-Can I sit down for a quick moment?
一瞬だけですよ｡
You have one moment.
うお～っ！お邪魔しま～す！
Whoa! Coming in!
うおお！すげっ！すっげぇ！
Wow, this is great!
《ナンバ･ムッタ飛行士
準備はいいか？》
Nanba Mutta, are you ready to go?
準備はいいかだって？
Am I ready?
ガキの頃からずっと
この発射を待ってたさ｡
I've been ready since I was a kid.
何？天候が怪しくなってきた？
What? The weather isn't looking good?
Don't worry about it.
そんなもん気にすんな｡
つべこべ言ってないで➡
Stop dawdling, and light this giant candle.
さっさとこのでかいキャンドルに
火をともしたらどうだい？
君の一瞬は何分あるんですか？
How many minutes will your quick moment take?
すいません｡
今日はまず オリオン宇宙船の➡
S-Sorry about that...
Today, we'll start by learning about the Orion spacecraft.
がいよう
概要から始めます｡
はい！
Yes, sir!
Three more laps!
(飛行士)あと３周！
(飛行士たち)はい！
(新田)まさか南波に
先を越されるとはね｡
I didn't expect Nanba to beat us into space...
僕はなんとなく
そうなるような気もしてたから➡
I had a feeling it would happen, so I wasn't all that shocked.
ショックも ほどほどだったよ｡
この先 俺ら…ど～なんのかね｡
What's going to happen to us now?
(ケンジ)そうだな…｡
Good question.
次はあんたよ ケンジ｡
You're up next, Kenji.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)失礼します｡
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)どうぞ ミスター･マカベ｡
Excuse me.
Come in, Mr. Makabe.
こっちで話そうか｡
Let's talk over here.
はい｡
Yes, sir.
君も かけなさい｡
失礼します｡
Have a seat.
Thank you.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)《｢座って話そう｣…》
I was told to take a seat first.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)コーヒーを頼む｡
はい｡
Could you bring us coffee?
Yes, sir.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)《その…いつもと違う
室長の気遣いに➡
And the chief was being unusually considerate.
僕は なんとなく
悟ってしまった…》
That was when I knew...
I see how it is...
《ああ…そうか…➡
僕は…月へ行けないんだな…》
I won't get to go to the moon.
わかっておいて
もらいたいのだが…➡
I want to make something clear.
“ナンバ･ムッタが
君より優れている"➡
We are not saying that Nanba Mutta is a better astronaut than you.
ということでは
決してない｡➡
I'm sure that after undergoing NEEMO training with him, you can understand our decision
ニーモ
ＮＥＥＭＯ訓練で
彼と一緒に過ごした君なら➡
理解できる部分もあるだろう｡
なぜナンバ･ムッタが
“月ミッション"に選ばれたのか｡
to send Nanba Mutta to the moon.
はい 十分 納得のいく人選です｡
Yes, I fully agree with your decision.
《正直なところ｢じゃあ
ここまで ずっとやってきた➡
Honestly, this makes me wonder why I've been training for the moon
月の訓練は何だったんだ｣
という気持ちもわいた…｡➡
for such a long time.
わかってる…
当たり前と言えば当たり前…｡➡
I know... The answer is obvious.
What took a very long time to build up
いつだって積み上げていく
過程は途方もなく➡
takes mere moments to destroy.
崩れ去るのは一瞬だ》
《それで その後 どうするか…》
So what happens next?
少し先に
なってしまうだろうが…➡
It will probably take some time.
この先 君が
宇宙へ行くと決まった その時…｡
But when you are chosen to go to space...
現在
この先 俺ら
ど～なんのかね…｡
What's going to happen to us now?
そうだな…➡
Good question.
｢月へは行けない｣か…｡
We don't get to go to the moon...
でも 僕らは
宇宙飛行士だからね 新田君｡
But we're still astronauts, Nitta.
宇宙飛行士をやめない限り
｢宇宙｣へは きっと行ける｡
As long as we don't give up on being astronauts, we'll make it into space eventually.
まあ そうだな｡
Yeah, that's true.
大気圏を突き抜けたところで
とりあえず夢は１つ叶う｡
Exiting the atmosphere is an accomplishment in itself.
ただ気になるのは…➡
But I'm curious about Chief Butler's last words.
バトラー室長の
あの最後の言葉だな｡
こまち
(小町)あ～ おったおった！
ケンちゃん レイちゃん➡
Oh, there you are, Ken... Rei.
I've been looking for you.
探したで～！
小町さん｡
Komachi.
２人の今日のスケジュール
ちょっと変更になったんや｡
There's been a change in your schedule for the day.
You're about to get real busy!
なんや これから
がっつり忙しなるで～｡
え…忙しく？
意外だな｡
Huh? Busy?
That's a surprise.
ほな行くでぇ～
ＮＢＬで無重量訓練や｡
Let's get going.
You'll be undergoing zero-gravity training in the NBL.
船外無重量…｡
てことは ＩＳＳか…？
Zero-gravity training?
Does that mean prepping for the ISS?
《無重量か…》
Zero gravity, huh?
ふうか
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)ごめんな 風佳｡➡
Sorry, Fuuka.
Unfortunately, it seems
残念だけど…
月には行けなくなったんだ｡
I won't be going to the moon.
Why won't you be going to the moon?
(風佳)なんで？
いけなくなっちゃったの？
Why, indeed?
ヤダァー！だってパパ
つきにいくって いってた！➡
That sucks!
You said you were going to the moon!
That's what you said!
つきにいくって！
なんでなんで～？➡
So why not?
That really sucks!
やだやだ～！あ～!!
Jeez! Building this took forever!
もう～！せっかく
ここまで つんだのにぃ～!!➡
あ～～！あ～～!!あ～～!!
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)なあ 風佳｡
(風佳)あ～～!!あ～～!!
You know, Fuuka...
また積めばいいよ｡
You can always start over.
やだ｡
I don't wanna.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)次は もっと上手く
積めるようになってるよ｡
Next time around, you'll do a better job.
現在
声聞こえる？新田君｡
(無線:新田の声)ああ 聞こえるよ｡
Can you hear me, Nitta?
Yeah, I hear you.
僕も気になってたんだ
室長の最後の言葉｡
I was also wondering about the chief's last words.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)⦅少し先に
なってしまうだろうが➡
It will probably take some time.
君が 宇宙へ行くと
決まった その時…⦆
But when you are chosen to go to space,
⦅きっと君は
さいはい
我々の この采配の意味を…➡
you will understand why we decided on
理解できるはずだ…⦆
these assignments.
どういうことだろうね…｡
What did he mean?
(ｵﾘﾋﾞｱ)いよいよね ヒビト｡
This is it, Hibito.
Yeah.
(ｵﾘﾋﾞｱ)大丈夫 いつも通りね｡
ＯＫ｡
Don't worry. Just act normally.
Okay.
(ﾛｰﾘｰ)ボ…ボクも しっかり
見届けるよ ヒビト｡
I'll b-be here to watch you succeed, Hibito.
ありがと ローリー｡
なに 俺より緊張してんの｡
Thanks, Lowry.
Why are you more nervous than I am?
どうぞ｡
Here you go.
(ﾛｰﾘｰ)⦅という訳で➡
And so, I told him that you're a big fan of Japan...
オリビアも超 日本ファンだって
言っちゃったんだ⦆
(ｵﾘﾋﾞｱ)⦅私が これ着んの!?⦆
I'm supposed to wear these?
⦅お願いだよ リアリティを
持たせるために⦆
Pretty please? We have to make my lie real...
Beautiful
⦅イッツ ビューティフォー！⦆
It's beautiful!
Beautiful
⦅ところで ヒビト…⦆
(ﾛｰﾘｰ)⦅ああ…⦆
So, Hibito...
Sh-She's wearing my T-shirt!
《僕のＴシャツ
着てくれてる～！》
あ ありが…｡
Th-Thank—
Okay, then.
≪よし…と！≫
R-Right...
よし！
I'm good.
準備はいいな ヒビト｡
Are you ready, Hibito?
そりゃあもう｡
You bet.
The starlight illuminates my future, it's wow... truth
It's 3 AM, and I dream awake
With no idea of my future
only impatience consumes me
I have a thorn in my heart that won't allow me to lose to him
I'm walking a path of thorns I made for myself
But I won't forget the love I found
And I won't forget the ones close to me
I realized you cannot live your life alone
The starlight illuminates my future, and we are all shooting stars
My holy wishes turn all our sad lies into something better
Our orbits have gotten separated,
but I'm fine if you are close
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#90 A Small Note and a Big Lucky Charm
It's finally time for the active duty test.
＜ついに復帰試験が始まる｡
大丈夫｡これで全てが終わる＞
It's okay. This is the last step.
The question is where you go from here, Hibito.
＜問題は ここからだ｡日々人｡➡
Can you cope with this surprise?
この追い打ちに耐えられるか？＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"A Small Note and a Big Lucky Charm"